ngccoin.com 2017-06-06

# Privacy Policy | NGC

This website is operated by the Certified Collectibles Group (“CCG”)

This Privacy Policy covers how CCG (also “we” or “us”) collects, uses, retains, processes, discloses and transfers Personal Information on the websites of the CCG Companies and on our mobile applications NGC and NGC Coin Details (together the “Site” or the “Website”). The websites of the CCG companies include:

  * Numismatic Guaranty Corporation (NGC): [www.ngccoin.com](https://www.ngccoin.com/), [www.ngccoin.co.za](http://www.ngccoin.co.za/), [www.ngccoin.cn](https://www.ngccoin.cn/), [www.ngccoin.hk](https://www.ngccoin.hk/), [www.ngccoin.jp](http://www.ngccoin.jp/), [www.ngccoin.sg](http://www.ngccoin.sg/), [www.ngccoin.kr](http://www.ngccoin.kr/), [www.ngccoin.tw](http://www.ngccoin.tw/), [www.ngccoin.de](https://www.ngccoin.de/), [www.ngccoin.es](http://www.ngccoin.es/), [www.ngccoin.fr](http://www.ngccoin.fr/), [www.ngccoin.it](http://www.ngccoin.it/), [www.ngccoin.pl](http://www.ngccoin.pl/), [www.ngccoin.ru](http://www.ngccoin.ru/), [www.ngccoin.ch](http://www.ngccoin.ch/) and [www.ngccoin.co.uk](http://www.ngccoin.co.uk/)
  * Paper Money Guaranty (PMG): [www.pmgnotes.com](https://www.pmgnotes.com/), [www.pmgnotes.cn](https://www.pmgnotes.cn/), [www.pmgnotes.hk](https://www.pmgnotes.hk/), [www.pmgnotes.kr](https://www.pmgnotes.kr/) and [www.pmgnotes.tw](https://www.pmgnotes.tw/)
  * Certified Guaranty Company (CGC): [www.cgccomics.com](http://www.cgccomics.com/), [www.cgcmagazines.com](http://www.cgcmagazines.com/), [www.certifiedguaranty.com](http://www.certifiedguaranty.com/)
  * Classic Collectible Services (CCS): [www.ccspaper.com](http://www.ccspaper.com/)
  * Certified Collectibles Group (CCG): [www.collectiblesgroup.com](https://www.collectiblesgroup.com/) and [www.collectors-society.com](http://www.collectors-society.com/)

Personal Information includes information about you that is personally identifying such as your name, email address, postal address and phone number and which is not otherwise publicly available. Personal Information may include other types of information depending on the legal definition that applies in your physical location. Only the legal definition of Personal Information that applies in your location will apply to you under this Privacy Policy.

### Agreement

**By using the Site and by providing information to the Site, you accept and hereby expressly consent to our collection, use, retention, processing, disclosure and transfer, including cross-border transfer, of your Personal Information in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy.**

This Privacy Policy may change from time to time, so please check back periodically to check the most recent modification date to ensure that you are aware of any changes in our processing of your Personal Information. Your continued use of the Site, our products or services after any changes signifies your express consent to any such changes. If you do not agree to such changes, you must immediately stop using the Site. This Privacy Policy was last modified on May 27, 2016.

### Information Collection and Use; Choice and Consent

You may browse the Site and access certain services, such as educational resources, chats and message boards, without signing up for membership or providing us with information, although your IP address will be collected when you browse the Site. If you wish to access our members-only features and content (“Members-Only Services”), you must register for membership and provide the requested information, which includes Personal Information. Providing Personal Information to use or access any of the Members-Only Services, and to access other services which request your Personal Information, is completely voluntary and is by opt-in only. If you do not opt-in, you will not be able to access certain features and services on the Site, and you will not be able to participate in Members-Only Services. By opting in to provide Personal Information, you are providing your voluntary and express consent to the collection, use, retention, processing, transfer, and disclosure, including international transfer and disclosure, of your Personal Information as explained in this Privacy Policy.

When you register for free membership, we collect your first and last name, country, public name, email address, and password. When you register for a paid membership, we also collect your credit card number, credit card expiration date, CVV, billing postal code, billing street address, shipping address and phone number. When you log in, we collect your username and password. We use this information to create and manage your account and your member profile, to contact you about your account and submissions, and to send you email newsletters, promotional emails, and other promotional materials if you have opted in to receive them. We may in the future use your Personal Information to send text messages or push notifications relating to our services and your account.

When you contact us for information or support through the Contact Us page, by email or by clicking on a service email address, we collect your email address, name and phone number in order to respond to you.

When you apply for a job on our careers page by faxing or emailing us your resume or C.V., we collect your email address and the information you submit to us, which may include other Personal Information. We use this information to assess your qualifications for the job you applied for and to contact you for an interview if we choose to do so. We will retain your information in case additional positions become available.

When you submit an item for grading or other purposes, we collect your name, phone number, email, postal address and payment information including a credit card number. We use this information to contact you about your submission, to process your transaction, to provide the services you request and to return your submission to you once grading and other requested services are completed.

If you register your collectibles in the NGC, PMG or CGC Registry programs and provide your collection information we will display it publicly on the Site. We will add this information to your profile. You may also choose to add collectibles to your profile without having them displayed publicly.

If you choose to post messages in our message boards, chat rooms or other message areas or leave feedback for other users, we will collect the information you choose to disclose and we may add it to your profile. If you send us personal correspondence, such as e-mails or letters, or if other users or third parties send us correspondence about your activities or postings on the site, we may collect the information and we may add it to your profile.

When you use our mobile apps NGC and NGC Coin Details, we collect your user ID to identify individual users.

It is always your choice whether or not to provide us with Personal Information. If you do provide Personal Information to the Site, you are giving your voluntary and express consent to the collection, use, processing, retention, transfer and disclosure, including international transfer and disclosure, of your Personal Information as described in this Privacy Policy. If you choose not to provide the requested information you may not be able to access certain features or functions of this Site, including the Members-Only Services. You may access, change, modify or delete your information, at any time, as described below.

You may opt out from receipt of our emails by clicking “unsubscribe” at the bottom of the emails you receive from us or by opting out in the “Email Settings” section of “My Account” on our website. You have the right to object to the use of your Personal Information for direct marketing purposes by email, on a going forward basis, by emailing us at [Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com](mailto:Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com).

You may revoke your consent, and/or object to or block processing of your Personal Information by emailing a request to us at [Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com](mailto:Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com). We will respond to your request in accordance with the law that applies to you. Your Personal Information which we processed prior to your request may not be deleted from our Site system records but will be blocked from further processing without your permission. A request to revoke consent or block processing of your Personal Information may not apply to information collected by cookies or used internally to recognize you and/or facilitate your visits to the Site, or information we may keep to comply with legal requirements.

### Cookies

When you visit the Site, we use session “cookies,” a piece of information stored on your computer temporarily, to allow us to uniquely identify your browser while you are browsing or interacting with the Site. Session cookies also help us confirm your identity and are required in order to log into your account. If you wish to prevent cookies from being used as you navigate our Site, you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies and/or indicate when a cookie is being sent.

Users who disable their web browsers’ ability to accept cookies will be able to browse the Site, but will not be able to access or take advantage of all of the features and services on the Site. We therefore recommend you do not block or disable these cookies. To find out more about cookies, including how to see what cookies have been sent and how to manage, as well as delete them, visit [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

### Google Analytics

The Web Site uses Google Analytics. For more information about Google analytic cookies, please see Google's help pages and privacy policy:

Google has developed the Google Analytics opt-out browser add-on for the Google Analytics JavaScript (ga.js, analytics.js, dc.js). If you want to opt out of Google Analytics, you can download and install the add-on for your web browser [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/).

To learn more about our cookies, see our Cookie Statement at ngccoin.com/cookies.

### Protection of Your Information

We will take appropriate technical and organizational safeguards to protect Personal Information from theft, other loss, misuse, and any unauthorized access, copying, collection, use, disclosure, alteration or destruction. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the Personal Information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, we cannot guarantee its absolute security.

We will retain Personal Information for as long as necessary to provide our services. We will retain and use Personal Information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

### Information Sharing and Disclosure

Information that is collected by any of the websites named above is shared with affiliates in the CCG group of companies for their internal and direct marketing purposes, consistent with any necessary consents. We share your Personal Information with third parties necessary to enable us to provide the Services and with third parties that perform telemarketing and direct marketing on our behalf (our “Subcontractors”). For example, we disclose Personal Information to Authorize.net, our payment provider, to enable them to process your membership payments. The Authorize.net privacy policy is available at [www.authorize.net/company/privacy/](http://www.authorize.net/company/privacy/). Our Subcontractors are contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality of your Personal Information consistent with the terms of this Policy and to comply with the applicable data protection laws.

We may disclose non-personal information and de-identified aggregate information to Google Analytics or other third parties.

We will disclose your information in response to valid legal process, for example, in response to a court order, a subpoena or other legal request for information, and/or to comply with applicable legal and regulatory reporting requirements. We also may disclose your information in response to a law enforcement agency's request or other request for information from the U.S. or other government entities, or where we believe it is necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, or to verify or enforce compliance with our policies and with applicable laws, or as otherwise required or permitted by law or consistent with legal requirements.

In addition, we may transfer your information to an entity or individual that acquires, buys, or merges with CCG or our other business units. You will be notified in advance of any rights you may have to block or object to this transfer of your information.

### International or Cross-Border Transfer of Your Personal Information and Your Express Agreement

Given that the Internet operates in a global environment and that transfer of your data is necessary to process your registration, to enable you to use the features and services on the Site, to provide updates, and to respond to your inquiries, using the Internet to collect and process Personal Information necessarily involves the transmission of data on an international, or cross-border, basis. By signing up for or using the Services, and/or by communicating with us by email, you acknowledge and expressly consent to our processing and disclosure of your Personally Identifiable Information in this way. The Personally Identifiable Information of users who are located outside the U.S. will be transferred outside of each eligible country to the United States where our servers are located and where it will be processed and stored on servers in the U.S. The U.S. has not been recognized as providing an adequate level of protection according to European Union (EU) data protection requirements, but we will take all steps reasonably necessary to ensure that users’ Personally Identifiable Information is treated securely in respect of such transfer and as described in this Privacy Policy. **By using the Site and by providing information to the Site, you expressly agree to such transfer, processing, storage and disclosure in countries outside the EU.**

### Links to Other Sites; Transactions with Third Parties

The Site may contain links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by CCG. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of these other sites. We encourage you to review the privacy policies and statements of other sites to understand their information practices. Our Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by our Site and Services.

CCG is not responsible for and will not be a party to any transactions between you and a third party provider of products, information or services. CCG does not monitor such transactions or ensure the confidentiality of your Personal Information, including credit card information, for any third party transaction. Any separate charges or obligations you incur in your dealings with these third parties linked to the Site are solely your responsibility.

### Children

Our site is directed to individuals who are the age of majority or older in their jurisdiction of residence. We do not knowingly collect information from children. If you believe your child has provided information to the Site please contact us using the information provided below.

### Your California Privacy Rights; California Do Not Track Disclosures

If you are a California resident, California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits you to request information regarding the disclosure of your Personal Information by CCG or its subsidiaries to a third party for the third party's direct marketing purposes. Since we do not make such disclosures, we are exempt from these reporting requirements. In addition, we currently do not honor Do Not Track signals.

### Accessing Your Information

You may access, review, change, update or delete your Personal Information, request information about our collection, use and disclosure of such information, and request information on our policies and practices relating to disclosure of information to our service providers, by contacting us at [Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com](mailto:Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com). We will respond to these requests in accordance with the laws that apply to you. You can help us maintain the accuracy of your information by promptly notifying us of any changes to your information.

### Contact Us About Complaints, Questions or Notices relating to this Privacy Policy

CCG commits to resolving complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your Personal Information. If you believe your privacy rights have been violated or you disagree with any action CCG has taken with regard to your Personal Information you may file a complaint with CCG by emailing us at [Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com](mailto:Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com).

If you have questions or suggestions, or wish to correct your Personal Information, please email us at [Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com](mailto:Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com).

### You may contact us at:

Privacy Officer  
CCG  
PO Box 4711  
Sarasota, FL 34230

Email: [Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com](mailto:Admin@CollectiblesGroup.com)

By Phone: +1 941 360 3994  
By Fax: +1 941 360 2553 

### Terms of Service

Please also visit our Terms of Service section establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of the website that is available in your location.
